# Mehdi Mahmud

Full-Stack Web Developer

15, Century way, B63 2TQ 👚

+44(0)7511118806 📞

mehdi.mahmud@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehdi-mahmud/ in

https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/portfolio/



# ABOUT ME /OBJECTIVES

Full-stack developer with a passion for coding and problem solving situated in the Birmingham area. As a skilled programmer, I can adapt to all stages of advanced programming. I am confident in my technical skills which range from coding and user interface to testing and debugging procedures. I hold a PhD in Applied Mathematics from the University of Birmingham and since 2000 I have gained experience in several different domains which include research, teaching, IT, and professional video editing. More recently, I completed an intense Full-Stack Bootcamp at the University of Birmingham, which I completed in November 2021 having obtained an overall grade of A+.



### **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate** | *University of Birmingham* 

May 2021-Dec 2021 Full Stack web Development

PhD | University of Birmingham

Oct 2015-Jul 2020 Applied Mathematics

"MICROBUBBLE DYNAMICS NEAR RIGID BOUNDARIES"

Msc | Salahaddin University-Erbil

Oct 2007 – Jul 2009 Computational Mathematics

"APPROXIMATION METHODS ON SOLVING A SYSTEM OF LINEAR 2D FREDHOLM INTEGRAL EQUATIONS"

Bsc | Salahaddin University-Erbil

Oct 1998 – Jul 2002 General Mathematics

"USING PRIMITIVE POLYNOMIALS IN **BLOCK CIPHER** TO CREATE A SECURE APP USING VISUAL BASIC"



### **EXPERIENCE**

### Research Fellow | University of Birmingham

SEP 2019 - JUN 2021

Research project: Wall Effects on Dynamics of Cavitation Bubbles around a Dental Ultrasonic Scaler. Here, I used ABAQUS and the finite element approach to conduct a numerical study for an ultrasonic dental scaler.

## **Teaching Assistant** | *University of Birmingham*

2015 - 2019

Teaching assistant- part time, during my PhD study in the school of Mathematics. I helped students in (Numerical Analysis, Computational Mathematics using Maple, Mathematical Biology, C++ programming and logic)

## Assistant Lecturer | *University of Salahaddin-Erbil*

2009 - 2014

Full-Time Assistant lecturer at Mathematics Department / College of Science to teach (
Introduction to Cryptography, Matlab, Visual Basic, Advanced Calculus, Computational
mathematics, Numerical Analysis)

## Teaching Assistant | University of Salahaddin-Erbil

2003 - 2007

Full-Time Teaching assistant at Mathematics Department to help student with (Computer programming using visual Basic, advanced calculus, Computational Mathematics using Matlab, Cryptography systems)

#### IT and video editor

2000 - 2014

Part-Time professional video editor in Iraqia Tv, Zagros Tv and Gulan Tv based in Erbil city. Also Helping in solving IT and technical related problems. I have used Adobe Premiere pro and Avid news cutter to edit news reports as well as tv shows.



### **S**KILLS

#### Web Languages / Technologies used:

✓ HTML ✓ CSS ✓ JavaScript ✓ Express.Js ✓ Node.Js ✓ Sequelize ✓ MySQL ✓ React ✓ Tailwind ✓ Bootstraps ✓ JWT ✓ Jest ✓ MongoDb ✓ ✓ Github
Other Languages
✓ Fortran ✓ Matlab ✓ Visual Basic

#### **Other Skills**

✓ Microsoft Office ✓ Adobe Premiere ✓ 3d Software (Abaqus)



## Personal Skills

I am an innovative problem solver who can work effectively in a team. As a critical thinker, I enjoy solving technical challenges and building projects from ideation to execution. I am confident in both leading a project or working as part of a team which I demonstrated during my time studying for the Bootcamp. I am also able to learn and implement new technologies. My previous work as a research fellow highlights my ability to give great attention to detail in order to effectively produce high quality work. I look forward to offering my skills as a Full Stack web developer in the future as part of a fast-paced yet quality-driven team.



#### Find all of my projects at: <a href="https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/portfolio/">https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/portfolio/</a>

#### InQuizitive

Senior Developer (Developing the BackEnd and Manage the FrontEnd React Framework)

#### MovieTime

Senior Developer (Developing the BackEnd and fixing the Problems in the FrontEnd)

### HolidayPlanner

Developer (WebPageStyling using tailwind and Api requests)



### **Publications**

Wang, Q., Mahmud, M., Cui, J., Smith, W.R. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Numerical investigation of bubble dynamics at a corner. *Physics of Fluids*, 32(5), p.053306.

Vyas, N., Mahmud, M., Wang, Q.X. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Imaging and Quantification of the Area of Fast-Moving Microbubbles Using a High-Speed Camera and Image Analysis. *JoVE (Journal of Visualized Experiments)*, (163), p.e61509.

Rostam K. Saeed and Mehdi H. Mahmud, Solution of a system of two-dimensional linearFredholm integral equation of the second kind by quadrature methods, *Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences*, Vol.3, No.3 (2009), 1701-1715.

Mehdi H. Mahmud and Rostam K. Saeed, Numerical Solution of System of Two-DimensionalLinear Fredholm Integral Equations of the Second Kind by Adomian Decomposition Method, *Proceeding of the 4th International scientific conference of Salahaddin University-Erbil*,October 18-20, Vol.1 of 4 (2011), 31-34.fa



### **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

- Bubble dynamics; Modeling Cavitation
- Boundary integral method
- Numerical Modeling; Computational Fluid Dynamics.
- Abagus ; Modeling Cavitation around ultrasonic dental scaler.